The race is won by the one who suffers the most
The Racer is a drama, comedy film directed by Kieron J. Walsh.
Summer 1998 - the opening stages of Le Tour de France are relocated to Ireland.
Belgian rider Dom Chabol (late 30s) has been one of the best
“Domestiques” (support riders) on the Tour for the last 20 years.
It’s a sacrificial role – setting pace, blocking wind, and providing support to
enable the team’s sprinter to victory - winning is not an option.
But Dom secretly harbours a desire to wear the yellow
jersey - just once before his career is over.
At the start of what will likely be his last Tour, Dom is
unceremoniously dropped from the Team he has dedicated his life to.
His best mate Sonny, the team masseur, fails to reassure him about his future.
But a chance liaison with Lynn, a young Irish doctor, softens the blow, and Dom
starts to accept - and even enjoy - the idea of civilian life.
But as he gears up to go home and to face his estranged sister, a massive doping error
knocks another teammate off the Tour and Dom is thrown back in the saddle…
Dominique Chabol, played by Louis Talpe.
Lupo ‘Tartare’ Marino, played by Matteo Simoni.
Dr. Lynn Brennan, played by Tara Lee.
‘Sonny’ McElhone, played by Iain Glen.
Viking, played by Karel Roden.
Stefano Drago, played by Timo Wagner.
The Racer is a 2020 sports drama film.
The film stars Louis Talpe, Matteo Simoni, Tara Lee, Iain Glen and Karel Roden.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.